

# LUIS PALACIOS





#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Experienced professional bringing successful 17 years of career in data analysis roles within large and fast-paced corporations. Release-planning specialist trained in advanced BI development, Oracle Hyperion Planning and MS Excel modelling. Creative solutions architect with real-time problem-solving flexibility. Proven ability to learn quickly and adapt to new situations.

#### **SKILLS**

- Business Intelligence: QlikView, QlikSense, Tableau, PowerBl
- Reporting: P&L, Cash flow, CAPEX, Balance, operational databases
- Financial tools: Oracle Hyperion Planning, HFM, Smartview
- MS Office: High Proficiency (especially Excel including advanced formulas, Pivot tables, Macros, charts)
- Corporate: +11 years experience in large corporation institutions
- OS: MS Windows desktop and Server, Mac OSX, Linux
- Data analysis: Python, R, SQL

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### Rivera Maintenance & Building | Windsor, On

Feb 2022 to Current

Cleaning Team Member

## Self-employed | Santiago, Chile **Financial and BI Consultant**

Apr 2021 to Nov 2021

- Maintain and Configure BI Server
  - Update BI financial dashboards.
  - Responded to specific BI requests from financial team personnel, creating data packets with requested information in easily understandable formats.

## Laureate Education Inc. | Santiago, Chile **Management Control Engineer**

Nov 2009 to Mar 2021

- Coordinate and lead activities related to the validation, mapping, cleansing, and conversion of financial data (P&L, Cash flows, Balance, CAPEX, operational data)
- Implemented an automatized process through QlikView and Hyperion, improving time reporting from 6 hours to 30 minutes.
- I trained financial teams in reporting in the best accurate way.
- Maintained and adjust reporting packages to senior management and operational reports to Hyperion Planning
- Gained extensive knowledge in data entry, analysis, and reporting.
- Responsible for daily enrollment reports to senior management
- Develop Business Intelligence (BI) solutions for the Financial, Marketing, Sales, and Legal department.
- Worked effectively in fast-paced environments.

## **DTS Chile.** | Santiago, Chile **Process Analyst and Quality**

Apr 2004 to Nov 2009

• Analyzed process flows and identified areas of improvement to increase productivity and reduce costs.

- Gathered documentation and created reports on asserted information.
- HP & Compaq customer service and technical support (call canter agent)

#### **EDUCATION**

St. Clair College Apr 2023

**Data Analytics for Business, Diploma** 

Windsor, Ontario. Canada

UEM Spain – UNAB Chile Jul 2020

**MBA**, Master Business Administration

Madrid, Spain – Santiago, Chile

Universidad Nacional Andrés Bello (UNAB)

Jul 2013

**Bachelor Business Administration** 

Santiago, Chile

Universidad Diego Portales (UDP) Dec 2004

**Computer and Information Systems Management** 

Santiago, Chile

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

Rivera Maintenance & Building
Employee recognition

Conferred for highlighted work performance.

Laureate Education Inc. Dec 2006

**Global recognition Collaboration Award** 

Global recognition conferred among all network financial teams. This Award was given for my contributions and share all my findings with my colleagues and other regional teams.

Mar 2023

LINKEDIN <a href="https://www.linkedin.">https://www.linkedin.</a>

https://www.linkedin.com/in/Impalacios/

**REFERENCES** References available upon request.